itracks.com 2018-09-06

# Privacy Statement – itracks

Interactive Tracking Systems Inc.

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you about the types of Personal Information Interactive Tracking Systems Inc. (as follows, “itracks”, “we” or “us”) collects about you in the process of conducting the principal activities of itracks as well as providing you with specific products and services you have contracted from us. It explains how we use and disclose that information, the choices you have regarding such use and disclosure, and how you may correct that information. This Privacy Policy sets out a summary of the principles and procedures that itracks follows in meeting its privacy commitments and complying with the requirements of the laws and regulations under applicable privacy laws in Canada and other jurisdictions, including the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act and the General Data Protection Act (GDPR).

Personal Information is any information that is identifiable to you. This information may include, but is not limited to, your name, mailing address, phone numbers, email address, identification numbers. Personal Information, however, generally does not include your name, business title, business address or business telephone number in your capacity as an employee of an organization.

We will treat Personal Information in a manner consistent with the Privacy Policy under which it was collected unless we have your consent to treat it differently. This Privacy Policy applies to any information we collect or receive about you, from any source.

**Principle #1- itracks is accountable for your Personal Information in its possession or control.**

itracks is accountable for all Personal Information in its possession or under its control and shall designate one or more persons who are accountable for itracks compliance with the following principles (Privacy Officer). Other individuals within itracks may be delegated to act on behalf of the Privacy Officer or to take responsibility for the day-to-day collection and/or processing of Personal Information. itracks is responsible for Personal Information  in its possession or control and shall use contractual or other means to provide a comparable level of protection while information is being processed or used by a third party.

**Principle #2 – itracks identifies the purposes for which it collects Personal Information from you before it is collected.**

We identify the purposes for which we use your Personal Information at the time we collect such information from you and obtain your consent, in any case, prior to such use.

Some of the primary purposes for which we collect and use your Personal Information include

  * to respond to inquiries you submit;
  * to conduct quantitative or qualitative market research
  * to send incentive payments for participating in market research
  * to invite you to participate in market research studies

In the event a customer of itracks provides Personal Information in order to purchase from itracks, we may use the Personal Information to provide services or product information to you in your capacity as a customer, however typically itracks customers provide business contact information.

**Principle #3 – itracks obtains your consent before collecting Personal Information from you.**

We explain your options and obtain your consent at the time of or prior to collecting, using or disclosing your Personal Information. We will always collect your Personal Information by fair and lawful means.  We also collect your Personal Information where we have obtained your consent to do so or as otherwise permitted or required by law.

Where is it reasonable to do so or permitted by law, we may rely on implied consent. For example, when sending e-mail messages of a commercial nature, reliance on implied consent is permitted to our customers or those who have recently purchased a product or services from us.

Providing us with your personal information is voluntary. You may withdraw or modify your consent at any time, subject to legal and contractual restrictions, provided that reasonable notice is given to us.

**Principle #4 – itracks discloses your Personal Information only for purposes for which it has consent, or as permitted or required by law.**  i **tracks retains Personal Information only as long as necessary to fulfill those purposes.**

itracks shall limit the collection of Personal Information to that which is necessary for the purposes identified by itracks.  We identify to whom, and for what purposes, we disclose your Personal Information, at the time of or prior to collecting such information from you and obtain your consent to such disclosure. In conducting market research, itracks limits the amount and types of Personal Information it collects.  We collect only the type of information needed for the purposes identified to individuals.

itracks shall not use or disclose Personal Information for purposes other than those for which it was collected, except with the consent of the individual or as required or permitted by law.  Personal Information shall be retained only as long as necessary for the fulfillment of those purposes.  itracks may disclose a respondent’s Personal Information upon consent to:

  * a customer of itracks where the respondent has consented to such disclosure;
  * a third party engaged by itracks to perform functions on its behalf;
  * a third party or parties where the respondent consents to such disclosure or disclosure is required or permitted by law.

itracks shall maintain reasonable and systematic controls, schedules and practices for information and records retention and destruction which apply to Personal Information that is no longer necessary or relevant for the identified purposes or required by law to be retained.

**Principle #5 – itracks endeavors to keep accurate, complete, and up-to-date, Personal Information in its possession or control, to the extent required to meet the purposes for which it was collected.**

Personal Information shall be as accurate, complete, and up-to-date as is necessary for the purposes for which it is to be used.

itracks shall update Personal Information about respondents as necessary to fulfill the identified purposes or upon notification of the individual.

**Principle #6 – itracks protects the privacy of Personal Information in its possession or control by using security safeguards appropriate to the sensitivity of the information.**

We have implemented physical, organizational, contractual and technological security measures to protect your Personal Information from loss or theft, unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use or modification. The only employees who are granted access to your Personal Information are those with a business ‘need-to-know’ or whose duties reasonably require such information.

Data collected in itracks qualitative market research software is stored in secure data centers located at the following locations:

  1. Rackspace – Chicago Primary Data Center  
2200 Busse Rd  
Elk Grove Village, IL 60007
  2. iland – Veeam Cloud Connect Partner  
1235 North Loop West  
Suite 800  
Houston, TX 77008  
(Rackspace backups)
  3. Amazon Web Services – US West (Oregon)  
(media file backups)
  4. Amazon Web Services – US East (N Virginia)  
(iMarkit media files)
  5. Saskatoon Secondary DataCenter  
150, 820 51st St.E  
Saskatoon, SK, Canada  
S7K 0X8
  6. Crown Enterprises Ltd.  
1414 Fletcher Road  
Saskatoon, SK, Canada  
S7M 5J4  
(Saskatoon backups)

You can visit our Web Site without telling us who you are or revealing any information about yourself, including your email address. However, our web server may collect the IP address and domain you used to access our Web Site, the type and version of web browser and operating system you are using, the number, duration and frequency of visits to our Web Site and the web site you came from and visited next. This anonymous information cannot be traced to a specific individual user, it is used by us simply to measure the number of visits, average time spent, page views, most popular preferences and other statistics about visitors to the Web Site and to determine the characteristics in which users use our Web Site and services. We may use this data to monitor Web Site performance for systems administration purposes, to make our Web Site easier and more convenient to use, to improve our services and to track information in aggregate form (e.g. how many visitors use the Web Site).

We use cookies, that is, small files that your Web browser places on your computer’s hard drive, to remember a user’s code, password and preferences while the user is using our Web Site and to facilitate navigating different pages on the Web Site.

Our Web Site contains security mechanisms that protect against the loss, the misuse and the modification of information under our control.

Our Web Site provides links to third party web sites. Our Privacy Policy does not extend to these third party web sites and it is recommended that users read the privacy policies of these web sites. We are not responsible for the content of, or the privacy practices employed by, third party web sites.

**Principle #7 -itracks is open about the procedures it uses to manage Personal Information.**

Up-to-date information on itracks’s privacy policies can be obtained from itrack Privacy Officer privacy@itracks.com.

**Principle #8 – itracks responds on a timely basis to requests from members or customers about their Personal Information which the itracks possesses or controls.**

We will make available to you any Personal Information that we have collected about you, utilized or disclosed, upon your written request. We will make such information available to you in a form that is generally understandable, including explaining any abbreviations or codes.

You can at any time, challenge the accuracy or completeness of the Personal Information we have which is related to you. Once we have validated your identity, we will amend the Personal Information as required. Where appropriate, we will transmit the amended information to third parties having access to your Personal Information.

Upon request, you can request the Personal Information be permanently removed.  This request will be granted by itracks in a timely manner.  Due to data backup procedures in place, this request may take up to 30 days.

We will attempt to respond to each of your written requests not later than thirty (30) days after receipt of such requests. We will advise you in writing if we cannot meet your requests within this time limit.

**Principle #9 – itracks will notify on a timely basis in the event of a data breach**

In the event that Itracks is aware of a data breach of Information which itracks possesses or controls, active customers effected by the data breach will be notified within 24 hours.  If there is exposure or potential exposure to Personal Information, itracks will notify affected individuals within 72 hours.

All comments, questions, concerns or complaints regarding your Personal Information or our Privacy Policy and practices, should be forwarded to our Privacy Officer as follows.

In writing:  
_Attn: Privacy Officer  
150-820 51st Street East  
Saskatoon, SK  
S7K 0X8_

E-mail: [ _privacy@itracks.com_](mailto:privacy@itracks.com)

We will inform you of the relevant procedures when you make an inquiry or lodge a challenge or complaint.

_Last revised: March 21, 2018_

EMAIL US

**Email:**  
( _general inquiries_ )

( _With support requests monitored 24 hours a day, we’ve got your back_ )

**Fax:**  

**Mailing Address:**  
820 51st Street E #150  
Saskatoon, SK, S7K 0X8  
Canada
